{
	"question_set_id": "a34acaa5-d40a-4339-9264-121e74258139",
	"topic_id": "806e2b8d-2d16-4138-abab-507ce429eacf",
	"tags": ["the-aircraft"],
	"title": "The Aircraft",
	"references": [
		{
			"text": "Waypoints Vol 05: PPL/CPL Air Law. Chapter 2: The Aircraft",
			"url": "https://www.waypoints.nz/products/vol-05-ppl-cpl-air-law-january-2017"
		}
	],
	"questions": [
    {
			"question": "Which CAA Part contains definitions and abbreviations of terms used in other parts?",
			"answer": "CAR Part 1",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "What is the definition of an aircraft?",
			"answer": "Any machine that can derive support in the atmosphere from the reactions of the air, otherwise than by the reactions of the air against the surface of the earth.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Give three examples of aircraft categories.",
			"answer": "Possible answers: aeroplane, balloon, glider, hang glider, helicopter, microlight.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1 (Aircraft category and category of aircraft)",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "How is 'Approved' defined by CAA Part 1, unless it's used with reference to another person?",
			"answer": "Approved in writing by the Director.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Which certificate is the flight manual specifically associated with?",
			"answer": "Certificate of airworthiness.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "CAR Part 1 defines the flight manual as containing __________ within which the aircraft may be considered airworthy, as well as what other information?",
			"answer": "Limitations. Instructions and information necessary to the flight crew members for the safe operation of the aircraft.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Does the definition of glider in CAR Part 1 include a powered glider while the engine is operating?",
			"answer": "Yes, 'includes a powered glider whether the engines are operating or not'.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "According to CAR Part 1, a helicopter means a rotorcraft incorporating one or more ________ ________ ________.",
			"answer": "Power driven rotors.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "Does the CAR Part 1 definition for maintenance include modifications?",
			"answer": "Yes.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-1",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "What is the maximum number of people a microlight can carry legally?",
			"answer": "2.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-2",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		},
    {
			"question": "How does CAR Part 1 define Operate, in relation to an aircraft?",
			"answer": "Fly or use the aircraft, or cause or permit the aircraft to fly, be used, or be in any place, whether or not the person is present with the aircraft.",
			"references": [
				{
				  "text": "Waypoints 2-2",
				  "url": ""
				},
				{
					"text": "CAR Part 1",
					"url": "https://www.caa.govt.nz/rules/Rule_Consolidations/Part_001_Consolidation.pdf"
				}
			]
		}
	]
}
